sierrawireless.com 2018-09-04

# Privacy Statement | Sierra Wireless

Sierra Wireless respects your privacy and is committed to protecting the personal information that you share with us. Generally, you can browse through our website anonymously without giving us any information about yourself. When we do need your personal information to provide services that you request, your information is collected, used, and disclosed in accordance with this policy. This privacy statement describes how we collect, use and disclose your personal information as part of our business, including on websites operated by Sierra Wireless under the Sierra Wireless domain such as sierrawireless.com, estore.sierrawireless.com, developer.sierrawireless.com, forum.sierrawireless.com and m2mexchange.sierrawireless.com. 

If you wish to update or remove your personal information held by us or adjust your subscription preferences, contact us by email at [privacy@sierrawireless.com  
](mailto:privacy@sierrawireless.com)   

## Information Collection

Personal information means any information that may be used to identify an individual, including, but not limited to, a first and last name, an email address, a home, postal or other physical address, credit card information, other contact information, title, occupation, industry, demographic and lifestyle information such as age, personal interests and product preferences or any other information about you collected in providing you with a service.

We automatically collect certain non-personal information regarding users of the website, such as IP address, operating system, region and language as well as the date and time the website was accessed, what features or pages of the website are accessed or visited and the websites visited immediately before you visit sierrawireless.com. This information is collected in order for us to analyze and improve the quality of our services and to develop aggregate statistics about our website use. This information is not linked to you as an identifiable individual. Please go to "Cookies, Web Beacons and Tracking" below for more information. 

Sierra Wireless collects personal information when you: create an account on our website; register to attend a seminar, webinar, participate in an online survey or access a whitepaper, ask to be included in an email, newsletter or other mailing list; submit an entry for a contest or promotion; purchase a product or service from our online storeask to contact our sales team directly; attend an investor event or trade show and provide your personal information to us; or submit your personal information to Sierra Wireless for any other reason. From time to time, Sierra Wireless receives personal information from business partners, vendors and distributors. Sierra Wireless uses personal information in accordance with this Privacy Statement and applicable laws. 

Access to certain Sierra Wireless web pages requires a login and a password. The use of those web pages, and the information or programs downloadable from those sites, may be governed by a written agreement between your employer and Sierra Wireless. Unless you request deletion of your personal information as specified below, your personal information may be retained by Sierra Wireless to verify compliance with the agreement, log software licenses granted, track software downloaded from those pages, or track usage of other applications available on those pages. 

When ordering a product from the Online Store, we need to know your first and last name, billing and shipping addresses, company name, telephone number, email address, and credit card information in order to process and ship your order. 

## Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies

Sierra Wireless may use non-identifiable information collected from visits to our web sites to help us provide better customer service. Sierra Wireless tracks website usage and measures web activity on Sierra Wireless websites, but we do so in ways that keep the information non-identifiable. This information is sometimes known as "click stream data." Note that information is only gathered while you are on Sierra Wireless websites. Sierra Wireless automatically receives such information from your browser and records it on our server logs. We use this data to analyze trends and statistics and to help us provide better customer service. 

Like many other commercial websites, we use a standard technology called a "cookie" to collect information about how you use the site. A cookie is a small data file that certain sites write to your hard drive when you visit them. A cookie file can contain information such as a user ID that the site uses to track the pages you have visited, but the only personal information a cookie can contain is information you supply yourself. A cookie can't read data off your hard disk or read cookie files created by other sites. Some parts of Sierra Wireless websites use cookies to track user traffic patterns. We do this in order to determine the usefulness of our website information to our users and to help users reach that information. This information is not reviewed at an individual level. If you do not want your transaction details used in this manner you can disable your cookies. 

Sierra Wireless websites may also use Web beacon or other technologies to better tailor those sites to provide better customer service. These technologies may be in use on a number of pages across our websites. When a visitor accesses these pages, a non-identifiable notice of that visit is generated which may be processed by us. These Web beacons usually work in conjunction with cookies.You can set your browser to warn you before accepting cookies and refuse the cookie when your browser alerts you to its presence. You can also refuse all cookies by disabling them in your browser; although you may not be able to take full advantage of Sierra Wireless websites if you do so. In particular, you may be required to accept cookies in order to complete certain actions on our websites. You do not need to have cookies turned on, however, to use/navigate through many parts of our website. We recommend keeping cookies enabled to experience the full capabilities of our website. 

We use Google Analytics remarketing codes to log when web visitors view specific pages or take specific actions on our website. This allows us to provide targeted online advertising in the future. If you do not wish to see this type of advertising from us, you can opt out using the [DoubleClick opt-out page](https://www.google.com/settings/ads) or the Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page.

## How We Use Information Collected

We generally use the personal information you provide when you visit our websites for the following purposes: 

  * to better understand your needs and provide you with better services;
  * for everyday internal business purposes in order to process your transactions, maintain your account(s), and provide customer service;
  * to manage, administer, collect or otherwise enforce accounts;
  * to keep you up to date on the latest product announcements, software updates, special offers or other information we think you would like to hear about either from us or from our business partners including sending you direct marketing information or contacting you for market research;
  * to maintain business records for reasonable periods as required by applicable tax and other laws;
  * to share information with your preferred distributor to ensure customer satisfaction;
  * to manage and administer our business, including defending and bringing legal actions;
  * to conduct market research in order to develop marketing strategies for Sierra Wireless;
  * to meet legal, regulatory, insurance, security and processing requirements; and
  * to identify you and protect you and us against fraud.

## Merger and Acquisitions

Circumstances may arise where, whether for strategic or other business reasons, Sierra Wireless decides to sell, buy, merge or otherwise reorganize businesses in some countries. Such a transaction may involve the disclosure of personal information to prospective or actual purchasers, or receiving it from sellers. It is Sierra Wireless' practice to seek appropriate protection for information in these types of transactions.

## Information Sharing and Disclosure

If you choose to provide us with your personal information, we may transfer that information, within Sierra Wireless or to third parties as provided for in this privacy statement. 

Sierra Wireless provides access to personal information about our customers only to those employees, contractors and agents who require it as part of their job in order to process customer payments and provide customer service. Sierra Wireless currently collects, stores and processes your personal information on servers located in Canada, but because of the global nature of Sierra Wireless’ business, your personal information may be accessed outside of Canada by authorized personnel who will then use and disclose your personal information in accordance with this privacy statement. 

Sierra Wireless may transfer personal information to outside agents or service providers ("Service Providers") that perform services on Sierra Wireless’ behalf, for example repair services, technical support, mailing, billing, marketing, information technology and/or data hosting or processing services or similar services, or otherwise collect, use, disclose, store or process personal information on Sierra Wireless’ behalf for the purposes described in this privacy statement. Some of these service providers are located outside of Canada, including in Europe, India and the United States of America. 

Sierra Wireless takes commercially reasonable contractual or other measures to protect your personal information if processed or handled by these Service Providers. While your personal information is located outside Canada it will be subject to the legal requirements in those foreign countries applicable to our service providers, for example, lawful requirements to disclose personal information to government authorities in those countries. 

Sierra Wireless may send your personal information to other companies or people as expressly set out in this Privacy Statement or under any of the following circumstances: when we have your consent to share the information; when we need to share your information to provide the product or service you have requested (such as sharing information with your preferred distributor); when we need to send the information to companies who work on behalf of Sierra Wireless to provide a product or service to you (we will only provide those companies the information they need to deliver the service, and they are prohibited from using that information for any other purpose); or if required to do so by law, to enforce our Terms of Use, in urgent circumstances, or to protect personal safety, the public or our websites. 

## Your Ability to Access, Review and Delete Your Account and Information

If you are receiving marketing materials it is because you have “signed up” on our websites for an account or with a sales representative to receive information from us. By opting in at the point of collection [by clicking the applicable opt in boxes] you have given us your consent to collect, use and disclose your information in accordance with this privacy statement. 

You may make a request to gain access to your personal information under Sierra Wireless’ care or control. Such requests must be in writing and require proof of identity. Sierra Wireless may charge you a minimal fee for providing you with access to your personal information. Sierra Wireless will respond to your request within thirty (30) business days, and will give you written notice if more time is needed or if your request is refused under applicable law. 

If you are a registered Sierra Wireless account user, you may request an update to or deletion of your personal information held by us by sending an email to: [privacy@sierrawireless.com](mailto:privacy@sierrawireless.com). If you want to unsubscribe from any of our email communications or other publications, please follow the unsubscribe instructions at the bottom of each publication you receive by email. 

## Data Security

Your Sierra Wireless account information is password-protected for your privacy and security. Sierra Wireless safeguards the security of the data you send us with physical, electronic, and managerial procedures. In certain areas of our websites, Sierra Wireless uses industry-standard SSL-encryption (128 bit secure socket layer). While we strive to protect your personal information, we cannot ensure the security of the information you transmit to us, and so we urge you to take every precaution to protect your data when you are on the Internet. Change your passwords often, use a combination of letters and numbers, and make sure you use a secure browser.

## Children's Privacy Protection

Our websites do not target and are not intended to attract children under the age of 13. Sierra Wireless does not knowingly solicit personal information from children under the age of 13 or send them requests for personal information.

## Third Party Sites

Our website may contain links to websites operated by other companies. Some of these third-party sites may be co-branded with a Sierra Wireless logo, even though they are not operated or maintained by Sierra Wireless. Although we choose our business partners carefully, Sierra Wireless is not responsible for the privacy practices of web sites operated by third parties that are linked to our site. Once you have left our website, you should check the applicable privacy policy of the third party website to determine how they collect, use, disclose, and otherwise deal with personal information.

## Local Regulations

The personal information directly or indirectly collected on the Sierra Wireless website is protected by local laws and regulations in the countries where Sierra Wireless operates. Sierra Wireless complies with all such local laws and regulations. 

## Changes to this Privacy Policy

If Sierra Wireless makes any substantial changes to this policy, we will make reasonable efforts to notify you of such changes by posting an announcement on the Sierra Wireless website. If we intend to use or disclose personal information for purposes materially different than those described in this privacy statement, we will make reasonable efforts to notify affected individuals, if necessary, including by revising this privacy statement. 

We urge you to review this privacy statement frequently so that you are aware of the most current version. Your continued provision of personal information or use of our services following any changes to this privacy statement constitutes your acceptance of any such changes. This privacy statement was last updated on June 30, 2014. 

## Questions or Suggestions

If you have questions or concerns about our collection, use, or disclosure of your personal information, or if you require any additional information, please contact our privacy officer at [privacy@sierrawireless.com](mailto:privacy@sierrawireless.com).
